Finding Aid for the Kenneth Rexroth Papers LSC.0175
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 39 boxes (19.5 linear ft.).
  - Subseries 1A: A-Z, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 35 boxes.
    - Schwartz, Horace., 1952-1972.; 38 items. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Schwartz, Selwyn--Seelye., 1941-1973.; 29 items. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Seghers, Pierre., 1954-1970.; 36 items. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Seizure Magazine--Seward., 1947-1975.; 35 items. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Shainsky--Shuffler., 1936-1975.; 79 items. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Includes 1 letter from Karl Shapiro (editor of Prairie Schooner), and 9 letters from Sheeds & Ward (publisher).
    - Sias, Dick and Beverlee., 1944-1958.; 20 items. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Sica--Silva., 1960-1973.; 16 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Robert Siegel.
    - Silver--Simbolica., 1960-1971.; 13 items. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Simmons--Simpson., 1958-1972.; 47 items. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Singer, Isaac, B.--Smith, Kathryn., 1951-1973.; 34 items. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Includes 2 letters from Isaac B. Singer.
    - Smith, Kimberly--Smith, William., 1946-1974.; 28 items. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Includes 13 letters from Kimberly Smith.
    - Smith, Leslie., 1923.; 5 items. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Smithback--Snyder, Bart., 1945-1972.; 22 items. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Snyder, Gary., 1954-1973.; 27 items. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Socialist America--Solomon, David., 1953-1969.; 9 items. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Solt, John., 1970-1975.; 56 items. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Something Else Press--Spector., 1952-1973.; 22 items. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Spectator--St. Edwards High School., 1946-1972.; 47 items. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - St. James Press--St. Sauveur, Frieda., 1949-1975.; 27 items. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Stafford--Stauffacher., 1948-1975.; 48 items. (Box 29, Folder 14)
      Includes letters from Ann Stanford.
    - Steel--Stephan., 1947-1971.; 49 items. (Box 29, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Ruth Stephan.
    - Stephenson--Stryker., 1955-1972.; 54 items. (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Stuart--Style., 1960-1975.; 22 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Subrahmanian--Swig., 1941-1975.; 55 items. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Phyllis Swig.
    - Swin--Szafran., 1957-1972.; 11 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Szerlip--Szold., 1970-1974.; 23 items. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Tagliazucchi--Tambimuttu., 1948-1974.; 26 items. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Thurairajah Tambimuttu.
    - Tamony--Taylor., 1945-1974.; 25 items. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from Nathaniel Tarn.
    - Teague Library--Tenth Muse., 1964-1974.; 9 items. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Thatcher--Three Hands., 1940-1975.; 49 items. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Tilton--Time Life., 1957-1968.; 25 items. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Tindell--Tinker., 1962-1973.; 31 items. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Tipton--Triem., 1941-1975.; 43 items. (Box 30, Folder 11)
      Includes letter and poem from Ruthven Todd (with possible T.S. Eliot signature).
    - Triest, Frank and Grace--Triest, Shirley., 1931-1974.; 40 items. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Tronslin--Tulane Drama review., 1937-1975.; 29 items. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Ulmer--Unicorn Press., 1958 - 1974.; 36 items. (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified., ca. 1920-1979. (Box 31, Box 32)
      11 folders of unidentified correspondence, arranged chronologically when possible.
    - Unitarian Church--United Jewish Community Centers., 1963-1972.; 7 items. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - United States Education Commission in the UK--United States. Department of Treasury., 1955-1967.; 22 items. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - University Books, Inc., 1959 - 1965.; 48 items. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - University of Arizona--University of Buffalo., 1940 - 1962.; 22 items. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - University of California, Berkeley., 1949 - 1971.; 24 items. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - University of California, Davis--University of California, Irvine., 1963 - 1974.; 12 items. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - University of California, Los Angeles., 1955 - 1971.; 16 items. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - University of California, Los Angeles. Library (folder 1 of 2)., 1945-1954.; ca. 150 items. (Box 32, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence between Rexroth and Lawrence Clark Powell.
    - University of California, Los Angeles. Library (folder 2 of 2)., 1955-1968.; ca. 150 items. (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections., 1960-1973.; 17 items. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - University of California Press., 1950-1973.; 9 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - University of California, San Francisco--University of California, Santa Cruz., 1960-1974.; 17 items. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - University of Chicago Press., 1953-1965.; 21 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - University of Denver--University of Massachusetts., 1948-1972.; 27 items. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - University of Michigan--University of Michigan Press., 1961-1968.; 49 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - University of Minnesota--University of Montana., 1959-1972.; 30 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - University of North Carolina--University of Southern California., 1956-1969.; 50 items. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - University of Santa Clara--University of Tampa., 1952-1975.; 20 items. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - University of Texas--University of Tulsa., 1959-1974.; 17 items. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - University of Utah--University of Wisconsin., 1948-1970.; 47 items. (Box 33, Folder 11)
      See also Morgan Gibson for additional correspondence regarding the University of Wisconsin, Madison.
    - Unmuzzled Ox--Utter., 1957-1970.; 12 items. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Vachel--Vetrono., 1928-1974.; 46 items. (Box 33, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from Mona Van Duyn, Dorothy Van Ghent, and J. Russell Vaughn.
    - Vice Versa--Vrin., 1940-1974.; 57 items. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - W. & G. Foyle Ltd.--Walker Art Institute., 1958-1973.; 32 items. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Del Walker, literary consultant.
    - Walsh--Weinstein., 1941-1975.; 65 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Weinstock--Weir., 1936-1937, 1968.; 5 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
      4 letters from Clarence Weinstock.
    - Weiss, Ted., 1944-1955.; 40 items. (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Editor of the Quarterly Review of Literature.
    - Weiss--Weston, Carol., 1946-1975.; 29 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Weston, Edward., 1931.; 3 items. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - WFMT--Why? [Freedom Press publication]., 1944-1975.; 40 items. (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from Philip Whalen and artist Emil White.
    - Widmer--Williams., 1944-1975.; 57 items. (Box 34, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence from Philip Whalen, artist Emil White, and Susan Wiere.
    - Williams, Jonathan (folder 1 of 2)., 1950-1959.; 83 items. (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Williams, Jonathan (folder 2 of 2)., 1960-1975.; 58 items. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Williams, Oscar., 1955.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Williams, William Carlos., 1930-1960.; 30 items. (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Williamson--Winston., 1947-1974.; 36 items. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Includes 1 letter from Edmund Wilson.
    - Winters, Yvor., 1929-1944.; 21 items. (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Includes drafts of Rexroth's letters to Winters.
    - Wisconsin State University--Witt Diamant, Ruth., 1953-1972.; 18 items. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Wittenberg--Wood., 1945-1971.; 30 items. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Woodcock, George., 1947-1954.; 38 items. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Woods--Xoregos., 1936-1975.; 35 items. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Yaddo--York., 1953-1975.; 26 items. (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from Yale University.
    - Yosemite National Park., 1962-1966.; 22 items. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Young--Youngreen., 1947-1975.; 14 items. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Zachreson--Zink., 1956-1973.; 29 items. (Box 35, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from Bernard Zacheim and Curtis Zahn.
    - Zondak, Brigit., 1958-1967.; 28 items. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Zuckerman--Zumwinkle., 1962-1967.; 4 items. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Zukofsky, Louis., 1930-1959.; 43 items. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Zweegman--Zweig., 1959-1963.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 1B: Cards, 1954-1975; 4 boxes.
    Birthday, Christmas, and miscellaneous cards sent to the Rexroth family. Box 36, folder 2 includes selected Christmas cards featuring original artwork or fine printing, or from prominent publishers, poets, or celebrities. Includes greetings from Leda and Stanley Burnshaw, Lawrence Clark Powell, Playboy, Jim Callahan, the Bronowskis, and Dick Gregory.
    - Cards., 1954-1975. (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
- Series 2: Esther Handler papers, 1957-1986; 2 boxes (1 linear ft.).
  Gift of Joseph S. Handler, 2004. An original pastel by Rexroth, part of the Handler gift, was matted and placed in box 159 during the 2005 processing. Arranged in Subseries A-B as follows:
  A. Correspondence, 1958-1986 (1 box).
  B. Miscellaneous, 1957-1986 (1 box).
  - Subseries 2A: Correspondence,., 1958-1986; 1 box.
    Arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent. Includes letters to and from Esther Handler and Kenneth Rexroth.
    - Gardner, Geoffrey., 1980-1981.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Georgia (surname unknown)., 1982.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Gibson, Morgan., 1983.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Handler, Esther., ca. 1960.; 13 items. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Hamalian, Linda., 1985.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Huerta, Alberto., 1981-1982.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Kodama, Sanehide., 1983.; 3 items. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Morita, Yasuyo., 1981.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Marcy (surname unknown)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Rexroth, Katherine., 1965 January 3.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 1 of 6)., 1958 May.; 10 items. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 2 of 6)., 1958 June.; 11 items. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 3 of 6)., 1958 July-December.; 16 items. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 4 of 6)., 1959.; 12 items. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 5 of 6)., 1960, 1963.; 11 items. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Esther Handler (folder 6 of 6)., 1964-1979.; 17 items. (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Rexroth, Marie and Mary., 1964, 1983.; 2 items. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Rolens, Lin., 1986.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Tinker, Carol., 1973-1986.; 12 items. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2B: Miscellaneous, 1957-1986; 1 box.
    Assorted materials. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Articles., 1967-1981.; 4 items. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Articles by Esther Handler, Alberto Huerta, Thomas Parkinson and Kenneth Rexroth.
    - Audiotapes., 1977, 1986.; 4 items. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Cassette recordings of Rexroth reading his poems to musical accompaniment.
    - Clippings., 1973-1982.; 6 items. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Ephemera., 1958-1982.; 9 items. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Includes a 1958 KPFA Folio, printed materials, and programs, including an inscribed program from Rexroth's 60th birthday celebration featuring a portrait by Richard Diebenkorn.
    - Photographs., ca. 1960-1980.; 7 items. (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Black and white photographs of Rexroth.
    - Poetry., no date.; 5 items. (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Typescript; author unknown.
    - Publications., 1957, 1980.; 2 items. (Box 41, Folder 10)
      Inscribed to Esther Handler by Kenneth Rexroth. Includes Saucy Limericks and Christmas Cheer (Santa Barbara: Bradford Morrow, 1980) and a Quarterly Review of Literature featuring "The Homestead Called Damascus" (1957).
- Series 3: Manuscripts by Rexroth, 1922-1976; 35 boxes (17 linear ft.).
  Original holograph and typewritten manuscripts by Kenneth Rexroth.
  Arranged in Subseries A-F as follows:
  A. Book reviews, 1937-1968 (1 box).
  B. Federal Writers' Project, 1936-1939 (1 box).
  C. Notebooks, ca. 1935-1950 (.5 box).
  D. Poetry and verse, 1922- 1967 (9.5 boxes).
  E. Prose, 1935-1976 (18 boxes).
  F. Translations, 1952-1974 (5 boxes).
  - Subseries 3A: Book reviews,., 1937-1968; 1 box.
    Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the author being reviewed.
    - Adams, Leonie; Bogan, Louise; Deutsch, Babette., 1953-1955.; 3 items. (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Typescript of omnibus review of books by Adams, Bogan, and Deutsch with handwritten annotations, plus clippings of photographs appearing with the published column; typescript of review of Bogan's Selected Criticism.
    - American Heritage., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Carbon typescript entitled "Advertisers anonymous; that $2.95 magazine." Published in The Nation, Oct. 29, 1955; v. 181, no. 18, pp. 358-9.
    - Art and Architecture of China., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Carbon typescript.
    - Baudelaire, Charles., 1957.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 4)
      Carbon typescript of Baudelaire, A Self-Portrait: Selected Letters, published in The Nation, v. 185, no. 33, July 20, 1957.
    - Bly, Robert., 1967 September 6.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Typescript review of The Light Around the Body, and A Poetry Reading Against the Vietnam War.
    - Buber, Martin., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 6)
      Carbon typescript of review of Buber's Hasidism and Modern Man.
    - Chicago in Fiction., no date.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 7)
      Typescript review of the University of Chicago's series.
    - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor., 1958 February 20.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Typescript review of Zen and the Notebooks of Samuel Taylor Coleridge, ed. Kathleen Coburn (written for the Chicago Review, but never published), and James Baken's The Sacred River: Coleridge's Theory of Imagination.
    - Daedalus., 1959.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Typescript review of special issue on myths and mythmaking.
    - Davidson, Donald., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Typescript and carbon review of Still Rebels, Still Yankees, annotated.
    - Durrell, Lawrence., ca. 1960.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 11)
      Typescript review of Balthazar, published in The Nation, v. 187, no. 116, Sept. 6, 1958. Galleys of review for The Black Book, published in The Griffin, Sept. 1960, annotated by Tom Lowry, managing editor.
    - Fromm, Erich., 1951.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 12)
      Typescript review of The Forgotten Language, annotated; note to Robert Hatch on leaf 3.
    - Gibbon, Edward., ca. 1956.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 13)
      Handwritten review of The Letters of Edward Gibbon, ed. J.E. Norton, published in The Nation, v. 182, no. 556, June 30, 1956.
    - Gruen, Victor and David R. Hunter., 1965.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 14)
      Typescript reviews of The Heart of our Cities by Gruen, and The Slums by Hunter; plus a letter about the review from R.B. Silvers at New York Review of Books.
    - Hatfield, Henry., 1951.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 15)
      Typescript review of Thomas Mann, published in the New Republic, Aug. 20, 1951.
    - Holmes, John Clellon., ca. 1958.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 16)
      Typescript review of The Horn, published in Saturday Review of Literature, v. 41, no. 11, Aug.2, 1958.
    - Lewis, Janet., 1946.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 17)
      Typescript review of The Earth-Bound.
    - MacKenzie, Findlay., ca. 1937.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 18)
      Typescript review of Society: Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow, ed. by MacKenzie, published in New Masses, New York (v. 24, no. 4, July 20, 1937), pp. 24-25.
    - Mannes, Marya., 1968 September 10.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 19)
      Typescript review of They.
    - Maritain, Jacques., 1968.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 20)
      Typescript review of The Peasant of the Garonne.
    - Martin, James J., 1953 July 12.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 21)
      Typescript review of Men Against the State.
    - More, St. Thomas., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 22)
      Typescript review of Utopia.
    - Parkman, Francis., ca. 1955.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 23)
      Typescript review of The Parkman Reader, ed. by Samuel Eliot Morison, published in The Nation, v. 181, no. 14, July 2, 1955.
    - Prokosch, Frederick., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 24)
      Typescript review of The Assassins.
    - Read, Herbert [book reviews and introduction]., 1945-1951.; 3 items. (Box 42, Folder 25)
      Typescript reviews of Art and Society and Collected Poems, published in the New York Times, June 17, 1951, p. 5; plus typescript of Rexroth's introduction to Read's The Green Child.
    - Rukeyser, Muriel., 1958.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 26)
      Typescript review of Body of Waking, annotated; plus clipping of published review from the New York Times Book Review, October 19, 1958.
    - Seligman, Kurt and Hutton Webster., no date.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 27)
      Typescript review of books about magic, annotated.
    - Singer, Isaac Bashevis., ca. 1953.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 28)
      Typescript review of Singer's Gimpel the Fool, and other stories.
    - Urbanism., 1964 January 8.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 29)
      Typescript review of books about urbanism.
    - Van Gogh, Vincent., 1958 November.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 30)
      Typescript review of The Complete Letters of Vincent Van Gogh, annotated.
    - Wei, Wang., no date.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 31)
      Typescript review of Poems by Wang Wei (translated by Chang Yin-nan and Leavis C. Walmsley), annotated. Note at bottom of page reads "To Francis Brown, New York Times Book Review."
    - Williams, William Carlos., 1955.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 32)
      Typescript reviews of The Desert Music, plus 1 leaf of commentary on Williams "written for San Francisco appearance at Poetry Center."
    - Yeats, William Butler., 1953.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 33)
      Typescript review of The Collected Plays of W.B. Yeats.
    - Yu-lan, Fung., 1953 October 7.; 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 34)
      Typescript review of Yu-lan's History of Chinese Philosophy, annotated.
  - Subseries 3B: Federal Writers' Project,., 1936-1939; 1 box.
    Manuscripts written while Rexroth was an employee of the Federal Writers' Project for the U.S. Works Progress (later Work Projects) Administration (WPA), which operated from 1936-1940.
    - Architecture in California II., 1938 September 19.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Camping in the Western Mountains--Illustrations., 1939.; 65 items. (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
      Original pencil and ink illustrations, and photostat copies. Includes a letter referring to the drawings from Franz Brandt, Supervisor, de Young Museum Project, N.Y.U.
    - Camping in the Western Mountains--Manuscript., ca. 1939.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 13)
      Annotated carbon typescript.
    - Camping in the Western Mountains--Notes., 1939.; 36 items. (Box 52, Folder 14)
      Handwritten and typewritten notes.
    - California guidebook materials., ca. 1936.; 7 items. (Box 52, Folder 15)
      Typescripts on Mt. Shasta, The National Tour (state line to Sacramento), the South fork of the Kings River, Mineral King, and Sequoia.
    - Field Handbook of the Sierra Nevada., 1939.; 1 item. (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Annotated typescript of 13 chapters. Incomplete; includes one leaf of notes outlining plans for chapter contents.
    - Material Gathered on the Federal Writers' Project San Francisco., 1936 October.; 5 items. (Box 53, Folder 2-3)
      Copies of anthology; newspaper clipping about the anthology.
    - Program for 1939 Northern California and San Francisco Offices Federal Writers' Project., 1 item. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Proposal for a Civil Service Registry for Writers., no date.; 1 item. (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Annotated typescript, incomplete.
  - Subseries 3C: Notebooks,., ca. 1935-1950; .5 box.
    Small personal notebooks containing addresses, thoughts and lists.
    - Notebooks., ca. 1935-1950.; 20 items. (Box 53, Folder 6-7)
  - Subseries 3D: Poetry and verse,., 1922-1967; 9.5 boxes.
    Arranged alphabetically, where possible, by the title of the manuscript or group of manuscripts. "Miscellaneous" folders contain poetry manuscripts that were filed together by Rexroth in unlabeled folders, and the original order was preserved at the time of processing.
    - Adam and Eve., 1961.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 35)
      Annotated typescript. Produced by the San Francisco Ballet, spring 1961.
    - The Art of Worldly Wisdom (folder 1 of 2)., 1949.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 36)
      First published in Prairie City, Illinois by the Decker Press, 1949. Printer's draft, with notations by Rexroth. Includes three handwritten letters to publisher Larry Decker regarding proofs and revisions.
    - The Art of Worldly Wisdom (folder 2 of 2)., 1949.; 3 items. (Box 42, Folder 37)
      Three additional versions of the typescript.
    - A Bestiary for My Daughters., 1960.; 2 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Handwritten illustrated MS with ink drawings; carbon typescript. First published in In Defense of the Earth by the Golden Goose Press in Sausalito, 1953, without illustrations.
    - Beyond the Mountains., ca. 1948.; 6 items. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Typescript drafts, some annotated. Contents: Phaedra. Iphigenia at Aulis. Hermaios. Berenike. First published in book form by New Directions in New York, 1951; also in Quarterly Review of Literature, NC, v. 5, no. 4, pp. 255-292.
    - Chinese Poems of Love and the Turning of the Year., 1969.; 100 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Loose typescripts and drafts.
    - Complete Poems, Volume 1., ca. 1950.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Binder of poetry, including works from The Art of Worldly Wisdom through The Signature of All Things.
    - Complete Poems, Volume II., ca. 1951.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Binder of poetry, including works from The Dragon and the Unicorn through One Hundred Poems from the Japanese.
    - The Dragon and the Unicorn--Annotated typescripts., ca. 1952.; 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      First published in Norfolk, Conn. by New Directions, 1952. Numbers delineating the sequence of parts do not correspond totally with the final order and arrangement of mss.
    - The Dragon and the Unicorn--Galley proofs., ca. 1952.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      With corrections.
    - The Dragon and the Unicorn--Selections and corrections., ca. 1952.; 2 items. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - The Dragon and the Unicorn--Typescript and errata., ca. 1952.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Earliest poems surviving., ca. 1930-1945.; 145 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Contents of a self-titled folder.
    - Eight Poems., 1937.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Carbon typescript with title page. Contents: Hiking on the coast range. It is later than you think. Requiem for the Spanish dead. Letter to W.H. Auden. At Lake Desolation. Remember now there were others before this. Gentlemen, I address you publicly. Shall ask no more (from The Crisis). Short holograph note in Rexroth's hand laid in.
    - Gödel's Proof., 1965.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Annotated typescript with title page.
    - The Heart's Garden, or, The Garden's Heart., ca. 1967.; 2 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Annotated typescripts, first published by Pym-Randall Press. Includes additional poems and translations.
    - The Homestead Called Damascus., 1920-1927.; 2 items. (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Handwritten and typescript versions; plus letter from Rexroth to his wife, Marthe, regarding his intent to seek publication. For oversize galley proofs with annotations, see box 158.
    - In Defense of the Earth--Annotated typescripts., 1950-1955.; 5 items. (Box 45, Folder 6-8)